<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tim Majarian | Tim&#39;s website - Under development</title>
    <link>https://tmajaria.github.io/author/tim-majarian/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tmajaria.github.io/author/tim-majarian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tim Majarian</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 15:10:55 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tmajaria.github.io/images/logo_hub8947cbc62e38556c2d597ea0394ffc8_30009_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Tim Majarian</title>
      <link>https://tmajaria.github.io/author/tim-majarian/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>GWAS in the cloud</title>
      <link>https://tmajaria.github.io/project/cloud_workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 15:10:55 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tmajaria.github.io/project/cloud_workflows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at the Broad Institute, I have developed a number of platform-independent tools for genome-wide association analyses. These workflows and notebooks enable scientists with varying computational experience, from first time programmers to experienced coders, to perform GWA analyses in the cloud. The tools span a typical GWA analysis, from file conversion to association testing to summary figure generation. Written in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://openwdl.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Workflow Description Language (WDL)&lt;/a&gt; with accompanying 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Docker images&lt;/a&gt;, each workflow can be deployed through most major cloud providers, as well as locally or on a high performance compute cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;try-out-the-tools&#34;&gt;Try out the tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, head over to the featured workspace 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.terra.bio/#workspaces/amp-t2d-op/2019_ASHG_Reproducible_GWAS-V2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;on the Terra platform for a tutorial&lt;/a&gt;. This workspace was developed and presented at the 2019 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ashg.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;American Society of Human Genetics&lt;/a&gt; meeting in Houston, TX. It is the product of a collaboration between 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://manning-lab.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the Manning Lab&lt;/a&gt; and the 
&lt;a href=&#34;broadinstitute.org/data-sciences-platform&#34;&gt;Data Sciences Platform&lt;/a&gt; at the Broad Institute. Special thanks to Dr. Alisa Manning, Allie Hajian, and Geraldine Van der Auwera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;access-the-workflows&#34;&gt;Access the workflows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each workflow is hosted on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dockstore.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the Dockstore platform&lt;/a&gt; and available for download or export to multiple cloud computing infrustructures. Access each below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File conversion: the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dockstore.org/workflows/github.com/manning-lab/vcfToGds:master?tab=info&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;vcfToGds workflow&lt;/a&gt; will convert variant call format (VCF) files to genomic data structure (GDS) format. GDS format is required to utilize the association testing and LD calculation workflows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Association testing: the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dockstore.org/workflows/github.com/AnalysisCommons/genesis_wdl/genesis_GWAS:v1_4_1?tab=info&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;genesis_GWAS workflow&lt;/a&gt; can be used for single- and multi-variant association testing using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/GENESIS.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the GENESIS software package&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linkage disequalibrium: the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dockstore.org/my-workflows/github.com/tmajaria/LDGds&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LDGds workflow&lt;/a&gt; is used to generate linkage disequalibrium measures from genotype data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza assembly dynamics</title>
      <link>https://tmajaria.github.io/project/influenza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 14:38:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tmajaria.github.io/project/influenza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within influenza virus infected cells, viral genomic RNA are selectively packed into progeny virions, which predominantly contain a single copy of 8 viral RNA segments. Intersegmental RNA-RNA interactions are thought to mediate selective packaging of each viral ribonucleoprotein complex (vRNP). Clear evidence of a specific interaction network culminating in the full genomic set has yet to be identified. Using multi-color fluorescence in situ hybridization to visualize four vRNP segments within a single cell, we developed image-based models of vRNP-vRNP spatial dependence. These models were used to construct likely sequences of vRNP associations resulting in the full genomic set. Our results support the notion that selective packaging occurs during cytoplasmic transport and identifies the formation of multiple distinct vRNP sub-complexes that likely form as intermediate steps toward full genomic inclusion into a progeny virion. The methods employed demonstrate a statistically driven, model based approach applicable to other interaction and assembly problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-more&#34;&gt;Read more&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1006199&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1006199&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
